Richard Eldridge

SUMMARY:

Software Developer with 2 years full stack experience. Highly skilled and knowledgeable at scripting, creating high functioning user-interfaces, refactoring inefficient code, and object-oriented-programming due to my experience with numerous API integrations, creating multiple subsystems, and modernizing legacy code. Well-versed in professional communication, troubleshooting complex problems, working with remote team members, and e-commerce business operations.

CONTACT:

Richardaeld@gmail.com

Projects Website
GitHub

LinkedIn

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Atlanta Network Technologies (antonline)

Smyrna, GA | Jun 2022 - current

Software Developer I

System Design

 Designed, created, implemented, and maintained sub systems for logistics and marketplace inventory integration. These new subsystems reduced code volume by 60% and increased code readability.

Extend Infrastructure

- Created a Linux and PHP solution that maintains data integrity by ensuring scripts run only 1 instance at a time.
- Employed Object-Oriented-Programing (OOP) to unify front and back-end code of internal logistics interfaces which increased readability and decreased code complexity and maintenance time by 80%.
- Designed and implemented an API that allowed JavaScript (JS) to utilize and call PHP classes and functions through the JS Fetch API.

API Integration & Maintenance

• Implemented and updated 3rd party API integrations using PHP scripts with OOP and Model-View-Controller (MVC) architecture. This reduced maintenance time by 50% compared to legacy integrations.

Create and Maintain Reports

- Developed a PHP API and new JavaScript architecture which enabled fully reactive reports and reduced required code by 50% compared to previous implementations.
- Improved the user experience of legacy reports by integrating JavaScript and improving their visual appeal.
- Modernized legacy reports by adding MVC and OOP architecture to decrease maintenance by 75% and while improving readability.

Monitor Logs

• Interpreted system logs to identify bugs, ensuring an optimal customer facing experience.

SGPS ShowRig, Inc.

Norcross, GA | Feb. 2015 - Jun 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control

SKILLS:

Languages

JavaScript

Java

PHP

CSS / HTML

Python

Tools

Linux

Git

Docker

Visual Studio

Code Google

Meet

Databases

Percona

MySQL

PostgreSQL

Mongo DB

Libraries

Node.is

Express.js

React.js

ACCOLADES:

Hack-a-thon Awards

1st Place Award- 2022 3rd Place Award- 2021

<u>Code Institute Projects</u> with Merit Distinction

Fat Raccoon Website Eldridge Music Emporium

EDUCATION:

Software Development Diploma *EU Accredited RQF Level 5 Diploma

Code Institute

May 2020 - Nov. 2021

Bachelor's of Computer Science

Kennesaw State University

**In progress - Senior